<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-11-01T16:57:34+00:00</updated><id>https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CUNY-nomic</title><subtitle>The game Nomic played as part of the course on Programming and Hacking Communities.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Minutes 2023-10-25</title><link href="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/10/25/minutes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minutes 2023-10-25" /><published>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/10/25/minutes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/10/25/minutes.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;minutes---programming-and-hacking-communities-meeting&quot;&gt;Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;10252023-1145am&quot;&gt;10/25/2023, 11:45am&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Chair:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Jonathan Hanon&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Secretary:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Sreehari Kalloormana&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Present:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Mikael Vejdemo-Johansson (MVJ), Jonathan Hanon (JH), Edward Miller (EM), Joshua Rollins (JR), Rose Wong (RW), Sreehari Kalloormana (SK),  Mark Schramm (MS), Zhiyuan Jin (ZJ),  Bilal Abdulrahman (BA)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting called to order at 12:26pm. BA not present when meeting called to order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal-for-agenda&quot;&gt;Proposal for agenda:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approving the agenda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approval of the previous minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unfinished Business&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull requests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-1-approving-the-agenda&quot;&gt;Item 1. Approving the Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves to approve the agenda. Seconded by EM. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-2-approving-the-previous-minutes&quot;&gt;Item 2. Approving the Previous Minutes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EM moves to suspend the rules temporarily to consider all the edits to the minutes as one. Seconded by RW. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several edits proposed, including, correcting MVJ’s initials from “MJV”, misspelling of “question” in line 79, switching the order of nays and ayes, subsubsubheadings for each pull request, line 100 to “6-1”, pull request numbering in line 114, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves to approve the minutes as amended.  Seconded by EM. Motion passess unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-3-unfinished-business&quot;&gt;Item 3. Unfinished Business&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pull-request-41&quot;&gt;Pull Request 41&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves to fix the spelling in the pull request. Seconded by RW.
Ayes: MVJ, EM, JR, SK, MS, ZJ, RW
Abstentions: BA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JR moves to amend the PR by restricting the maximum duration of the auction to 2 minutes, supervised by the chair. Seconded by MVJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MS proposes to add that at the end of the two minutes the person with the highest bid recieves the PR priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MS calls the question, seconded by BA. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ proposes an amendment to handle the pull requests as a priority queue. Seconded by BA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH proposes an amendment to the amendment to invoke the PR number in the case of equal priority, seconded by RW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH moves to suspend the rules of Robert’s Rules of Order to edit the wording of the statement of the PR from “spending” to “proposing to spend”. Seconded by BA. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ calls the question on the amendment to the amendment. Seconded by RW. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves to introduce a further edit to the amendment by changing an article to “a”. Seconded by BA. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JR calls the question on the amendment to the PR. Seconded by BA.
Ayes: MVJ, JR, SK, ZJ, RW.
Nays: EM, MS.
Motion passes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MS calls for a point inversion. EM seconds.
Ayes: MS, EM, BA, JH
Nays: MVJ, RW, SK
Motion passes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA proposes an amendment to state that everyone gets 100 points at the point of adoption of the rule. Seconded by ZJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ calls the question on the amendment. Seconded by BA.
Ayes: BA
Nays: MVJ, RW, SK, ZJ, EM, MS
Abstention: JR
Motion does not pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA moves to call the question on PR 41. Seconded by RW. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chair calls the question on PR 41. 
Ayes: MVJ, ZJ, MS, EM, SK
Nays: RW
Abstentions: JR, BA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SK raises a point of order on the permissibility of abstentions in voting on pull requests. Point well taken by the chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA moves to suspend the rules which do not allow abstainers to be counted among the participants in a voting. Seconded by EM.
RW objected to the suspension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PR passes as amended with 5 vs 1. BA loses 43 points. RW loses 10 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pull-request-52&quot;&gt;Pull Request 52&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ calls for suspension of the rules of NOMIC to combine the transmutation and change of rule 105 into a single vote, by proposing to spend 6 points to consider this rule change first. Seconded by BA.
BA calls the question on the suspension of NOMIC rules. Seconded by RW. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ spends 6 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA moves to call the question on PR #52. Seconded by MVJ. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question called by the chair on PR #52.
Ayes: MVJ, ZJ, MS, EM, SK, JR, BA
Abstentions: RW
Motion fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ loses 10 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pull-request-53&quot;&gt;Pull Request 53&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ creates PR #53 which creates a new rule to allow for abstainers to be counted among participants. 1 point proposed by BA to move to the top of the priority queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JR proposes an amendment to change the mutability status of the proposed rule. Seconded by BA.
Ayes: MVJ, ZJ, MS, EM, SK, JR, BA
Abstentions: RW
Amendment passes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH calls the question on PR #53.
Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PR passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ gains 63 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA moves to adjourn the meeting. Seconded by RW. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting adjourned at 1:45 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sreehari Kalloormana</name></author><summary type="html">Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minutes 2023-18-04</title><link href="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/10/18/minutes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minutes 2023-18-04" /><published>2023-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/10/18/minutes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/10/18/minutes.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;minutes---programming-and-hacking-communities-meeting&quot;&gt;Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;10182023-1145am&quot;&gt;10/18/2023, 11:45am&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Chair:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Mark Schramm (MS)&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Secretary:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Rose Wong (RW)&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Present:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Mikael Vejdemo-Johansson (MVJ), Jonathan Hanon (JH), Bilal Abdulrahman (BA), Edward Miller (EM), Joshua Rollins (JR), Mark Schramm (MS), Rose Wong (RW), Zhiyuan Jin (ZJ)&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Absent:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Sreehari Kalloormana (SK)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting called to order at 12:22pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal-for-agenda&quot;&gt;Proposal for agenda:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approving the agenda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approval of the Minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unfinished Business&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-1-approving-the-agenda&quot;&gt;Item 1. Approving the Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves to approve the agenda, seconded by EM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JR proposes to amend the agenda by adding Pull Request. Seconded by BA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final Agenda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approving the agenda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approval of the Minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unfinished Business&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull requests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA calls the question. Seconded. Proposal to amend agenda passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moved to approve the agenda as amended. Seconded. Approved unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-2-approval-of-the-minutes&quot;&gt;Item 2. Approval of the Minutes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EM proposes to amend line 39. Seconded by MVJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moved to amend Item 4d to “Motion does not pass, RW loses 10 points.” Passed unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moved and seconded by BA to amend line 186 to read “MVJ and ZJ win 10 points each”. Passed unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EM moves and BA seconded to suspend the rule to condense changes to minutes into one item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EM withdrew motion and seconded by MVJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MS motioned to approve the minutes. Seconded by BA. Minutes approved unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-3-unfinished-business&quot;&gt;Item 3. Unfinished Business&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No unfinished business&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-4&quot;&gt;Item 4.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pull-request-38-by-ba&quot;&gt;Pull Request 38 by BA&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ proposes to amend the rule change by “changing work individually on line 6 to simultaneously”. Seconded by EM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH motioned to call the question. Seconded by BA. Passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ayes: MVJ, JH, BA, EM, JR, RW
Nay: ZJ
Amendment passes 6 - 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ called the question. Seconded.
Ayes: MVJ, JH, BA, JR, RW, ZJ
Nay: EM
Question called 6 - 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ayes: MVJ, JH, BA, JR
Nay: EM, ZJ, RW, MS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule change 38 failed and BA loses 10 points&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pull-request-39-by-ba&quot;&gt;Pull Request 39 by BA&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves to change first sentence to read “anyone voting in favor of a failing rule change will gain 10 points.” Seconded by BA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH called to question. Call passed unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amendment passed unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH motions to strike the second sentence. Seconded by MVJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MS called the question. Call passed unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MS called to question. Seconded. Amendment passed unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA proposes amendment to change from 10 to 5 points. No second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH proposed “anyone voting in favor of a failed rule change that is not their own will gain 10 points”. Seconded. Amendment passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ called the question. Seconded. Call passed unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ayes: MVJ, JH, BA, JR, MS, ZJ
Nays: EM
Abstains: RW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule change passes 6 - 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Point gains: BA +35, EM + 10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA moved to postpone consideration of PRs #41, #42 until next week. Seconded by JR. Motion passed unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pull-request-43-by-ms&quot;&gt;Pull request 43 by MS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA moved and seconded by EM to remove “and amendments” Passed unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moved to amend last sentence starting with Mark S to “ a new officer of the role called the “records keeper” is instituted and elected from the participants whose responsibilitiy is to track and report the current max number of rules voted on and to track and report the chair rewards”. Seconded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ZJ moved to amend the amendment to “the secretary will tract and report…” Seconded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ZJ called the question on amendment to amendment. seocnded by MVJ. Passed unananimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amendment to amendment passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vote on amendment:
Ayes: MVJ, BA, MS, ZJ, EM, RW
Nays: JH, JR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amendment passed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA called the question on rule change. Seconded. Call passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ayes: BA, MS, JR, ZJ
Nays: JH, EM, MVJ, RW
Rule change failed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Points: +10 points each to BA, JR, ZJ,  -10 points to Mark&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pull-request-45-by-em&quot;&gt;Pull Request 45 by EM&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves to amend “introduce on line 5 “the dissenters is someone who votes against a rule change proposal or for a losing rule change proposal…” Seconded by BA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH moves to suspend the rules in order to allow this rule change to be discussed alongside the abolishment of rule 339. Seconded by BA.
Passes unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA called the question and seconded by MVJ. Call passes unanimously. Question is to amend “dissenter receives 10 points, if two dissenters 5 points each, if more than 3 no points”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ayes: MVJ, JH, BA, MS, ZJ, RW, EM
Nays: JR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vote on the pull request:
Ayes: MVJ, EM, JH, RW 
Nays: BA, JR, ZJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule change passes 4 - 3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Points +32 points to EM and +10 to dissenters JR, BA and ZJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pull-request-46-by-ba&quot;&gt;Pull Request 46 by BA&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ motions to suspend any Pull Request by BA. Seconded by BA. 
Ayes: MVJ, JH, BA, MS, RW, EM, JR
Nays: ZJ
Motion passes by majority&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pull request 48 by MVJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ayes: RW, JR, BA, EM, MVJ 
Nays: JH, MS, ZJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule change passes 5 vs. 3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Points: MVJ +36&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ZJ moved and seconded by MVJ to adjourn. Motion rejected unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pull-request-40-by-ba&quot;&gt;Pull Request 40 by BA&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves to amend proposal with 2 edits: insert word “only” instead of “during”, and “to be multiplied by negative 1”. Seconded by BA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MS moves to suspend rules to discuss edits. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves to change wording to “for the next rule change vote”. Seconded by JH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH proposes to amend “only on rule change that is currently on the floor”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ proposes edits to first clause&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH proposes and seconded by EM to suspend rules to consider all proposals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JR called the question (to amend the rule change). Call passes unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA called the question. Seconded by MVJ. Passes unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aye - RW, EM, JH, BA
Nays - JR, MVJ, AJ
Abstain - MS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule change passes 4 to 3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Points - BA +29&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA moved to adjourn MVJ. Seconded.
Meeting adjourned 1:51PM.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rose Wong</name></author><summary type="html">Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minutes 2023-10-11</title><link href="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/10/11/minutes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minutes 2023-10-11" /><published>2023-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/10/11/minutes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/10/11/minutes.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;minutes---programming-and-hacking-communities-meeting&quot;&gt;Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;10112023-1145-am&quot;&gt;10/11/2023, 11:45 AM&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Chair:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Zhiyuan Jin&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Secretary:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Joshua Rollins&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Present:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Mikael Vejdemo Johansson (MVJ), Jonathan Hanon (JH), Mark Schramm (MS), Zhiyuan Jin (ZJ), Edward Miller (EM), Joshua Rollins (JR), Bilal Abdulrahman (BA)&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Absent:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Rose Wong (RW)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting was called to order at 11:59 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal-for-agenda&quot;&gt;Proposal for agenda:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approving the agenda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approval of the previous minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unfinished Business&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull requests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-1-approving-the-agenda&quot;&gt;Item 1. Approving the Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agenda moved by ZJ, seconded by JR.
Approved unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-2-approving-the-previous-minutes&quot;&gt;Item 2. Approving the Previous Minutes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JH proposed to add MVJ’s suspension of the rules to combine abolishing Rule 112 and moving Proposal 312, seconded by JR.
The amendment to the minutes recording this passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH moves to amend the minutes seconded by MS.
The amendment to minutes by JH passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH moved to amend the minutes on line 76 to include that the item was specifically postponed to a meeting in which Mark was in attendance to consider the motion, seconded by MS.
The motion passed by majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moved to approve the previous minutes with amendments seconded by MS.
Debated by EM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ZJ moved accepting previous minutes as stated with amendments, seconded by MVJ.
Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-3a-pull-request-22&quot;&gt;Item 3a. Pull Request #22&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MVJ moved that the old pull requests, #22 and #23, are resubmitted in the new branch, seconded by MS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH moved to amend the motion to ignore previous business instead of considering it resubmitted and reviewed immediately, seconded by MVJ.
The amendment is adopted unanimously.
The motion from MVJ was passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-4a-pull-request-31&quot;&gt;Item 4a. Pull Request #31&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider Pull Request #31 by BA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moved to consider all 7 file changes in pull request #31 as a single unit, seconded by EM.
EM calls the question, seconded by MVJ.
The motion to call the question is passed unanimously.
Ayes: MVJ, JR, MS, JH
Nays: EM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moved that pull request #31 is considered incorrectly formatted as stated in Rule #104 and should be discarded, seconded by JR.
The motion passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-4b-pull-request-32&quot;&gt;Item 4b. Pull Request #32&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider Pull Request #32 by RW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EM motioned to recess for 5 minutes after considering the Pull Request, seconded by MS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moved to amend the Pull Request to agree with the rule numbering, seconded by JR.
Passed unanimously. The rule’s name was updated to 332.md.
JH called the question, MVJ seconded.
Calling the question passed unanimously.
Ayes: None
Nays:  MVJ, EM, JH, JR, MS
RW lost 10 points for having the proposal declined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EM proposes a 5-minute recess, seconded by JH.
The motion to recess passed unanimously.
Recess began at 12:45 PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA entered.
Called to order at 12:52 PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-4c-pull-request-33&quot;&gt;Item 4c. Pull Request #33&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider Pull Request #33 by RW, seconded by MVJ.
MVJ had already changed the numbering scheme to reflect our formatting considerations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moved to amend the second half of the second to “then any point gains by the lead player will be reduced by 50% until the advantage drops below 20 points.” Seconded by EM.
Ayes: MVJ, JH, EM, JR, BA, MS 
Nay: 
The amendment was adopted unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ called the question, seconded by JR.
The motion to call the question is unanimous.
BA called for a division of the house.
Ayes: MVJ
Nays: BA, MS, ZJ, EM, JH, JR
The rule does not pass, RW loses 10 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-4d-pull-request-34&quot;&gt;Item 4d. Pull Request #34&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider Pull Request #34 by RW, seconded by EM.
MVJ had already changed the numbering scheme to reflect our formatting considerations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA moved to amend the rule change to “add 10 then take the pull request number and then divide that pull request number by 10.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moved to put forth their own rule change. It is out of order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA called the question, seconded by MVJ.
The motion to call the question passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA moved to withdraw the amendment, seconded by MVJ.
Ayes: MVJ, BA, JR, MS, EM
Nays: JH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA called the question, seconded by MVJ.
The motion to call the question passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voting on the question:
Ayes: 
Nays: MS, BA, EM, JR, JH, MVJ
Abstain: ZJ
The rule does not pass, RW loses 10 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting has been recessed at 1:10 PM.
The meeting has been called to order at 1:13 PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-4e-pull-request-36&quot;&gt;Item 4e. Pull Request #36&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider Pull Request #36 by MVJ, seconded by BA.
MVJ had already changed the numbering scheme to reflect our formatting considerations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA moved to amend the rule change to add after the word integer “, and then add 10 points.” Seconded by MS.
MVJ moved to amend the amendment to 5 points instead of 10 points, seconded by EM.
Voting on the amendment to the amendment.
Ayes: EM, MVJ, MS
Nays: BA, JR
Abstain: JH, ZJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amendment to BA’s amendment passed by a majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MS proposed an amendment, where the prosper would write out the point addition they would expect. Amendment withdrawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voting on BA’s amendment amendment.
Ayes: MVJ, BA, EM, JH
Nays: JR, MS
Abstain: ZJ
Amendment passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voting on the rule change.
Ayes: MVJ, EM
Nays: JH, BA, MS
Abstain: ZJ
The rule does not pass, and MVJ loses 10 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-4f-pull-request-37&quot;&gt;Item 4f. Pull Request #37&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider Pull Request #37 by BA, seconded by EM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ objected to consideration of the question, EM seconds. MVJ withdraws his objection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JR proposed an amendment, that specifies that the game where they can wager points, seconded by MS. Passed unanimously. The amendment to the rule change is adopted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moved to change the numbering scheme to reflect our formatting considerations and fix spelling changes, seconded by EM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EM proposed the amendment to change “players can also wager their points in the beginning of the game”, to “players can also wager any points that they have accumulated in the game of nomic in the game of Fluxx.” Seconded by ZJ.
Passed unanimously. Amendment accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voting on the rule change.
Ayes: MS, JH, BA, EM, JR
Nays: MVJ, ZJ
The rule change has been accepted. BA wins 34 points. 
MVJ and ZJ win 10 points each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ZJ motioned to adjourn, seconded by EM.
The motion passed unanimously at 1:41 PM.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Joshua Rollins</name></author><summary type="html">Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minutes 2023-10-04</title><link href="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/10/04/minutes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minutes 2023-10-04" /><published>2023-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/10/04/minutes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/10/04/minutes.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;minutes---programming-and-hacking-communities-meeting&quot;&gt;Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;10042023-1145am&quot;&gt;10/04/2023, 11:45am&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Chair:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Edward Miller&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Secretary:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Sreehari Kalloormana&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Present:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Mikael Vejdemo-Johansson (MVJ), Jonathan Hanon (JH), Bilal Abdulrahman (BA), Edward Miller (EM), Joshua Rollins (JR), Rose Wong (RW), Sreehari Kalloormana (SK)&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Absent:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Mark Schramm (MS), Zhiyuan Jin (ZJ)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting called to order at 12:38pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal-for-agenda&quot;&gt;Proposal for agenda:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approving the agenda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approval of the previous minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unfinished Business&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull requests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-1-approving-the-agenda&quot;&gt;Item 1. Approving the Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agenda moved by JR, seconded by BA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ proposes to amend the agenda by processing Pull Request #26 (Proposal 315) first in Item 4, as Item 4a, with everything else under 4b. Seconded by JR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JR proposes to amend the amendment by moving Item 4a to 2a. Seconded by MVJ. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ calls the question on the amendment, seconded by BA. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH calls the question on Item 1, “Approval of the Agenda”. Seconded by MVJ. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-2-approving-the-previous-minutes&quot;&gt;Item 2. Approving the Previous Minutes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MVJ proposes correction of the minutes by fixing the spacing in lines 62, 65, 73, 88, 91, and 94. Seconded by BA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JR proposes to add correction of MS’s initial. This was subsumed to MVJ’s proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH proposes additional edits: fixing capitalizations, missing periods. Seconded by MVJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ proposes to consider all the edits as one. Seconded by BA. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves to approve the minutes as amended. Seconded by BA. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-2a-pull-request-26-proposal-315&quot;&gt;Item 2a. Pull Request #26 (Proposal 315)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JH moves to replace Proposal 315 with a rule change for Rule 208, seconded by RW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proposal number corrected from 315 to 312 by MVJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RW moves to amend Proposal 312 to say that “players with the maximum points wins”. Seconded by BA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH raises a point of order: The proposed amendment is in conflict with Rule 112. Point of order is well taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves to suspend the rules in order to consider both the change in mutability and the abolishment of Rule 112 together with proposal 312 as a single unit for consideration.
BA seconded.
EM calls the question. 
Nays: JR. 
Ayes: MVJ, JH, BA, RW, SK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EM calls the question on proposal 312 together with making 112 mutable and abolishing 112.
Nays: JR
Ayes: MVJ, JH, BA, RW, SK.
The proposal does not pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-3-unfinished-business&quot;&gt;Item 3. Unfinished Business&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JH proposes to postpone Item 3 until a meeting in which Mark Schramm is present. Seconded by BA.
Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-4-pull-requests&quot;&gt;Item 4. Pull Requests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider Proposal 315 by JR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RW moves to amend the proposal. No second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH calls the question. Seconded by MVJ. 
Nays: BA, SK, EM
Ayes: MVJ, JH, JR, RW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ calls for division.
Ayes: BA, SK, EM, MVJ, JH, JR, RW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion passes. 100pts added to everyone’s score. The first iteration of the game of CUNY-nomic ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH proposes to move to the next item on the agenda. Seconded by JR.
Ayes: RW, BA, JH, JR
Motion passes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-5-new-business&quot;&gt;Item 5. New Business&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MVJ proposes a 5 minute recess at 1:23pm. Seconded by BA. Motion passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recess extended for a few more minutes at 1:28pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting called back to order by EM at 1:33pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ explains the new rule sets for the next NOMIC game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EM moves to adjourn at 1:39pm, seconded by BA. 
Ayes: RW, EM
Nays: JH
Motion to adjourn does not pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EM moves to adjourn, seconded by JR.
Ayes: MVJ, EM, JR, RW, SK
Nays: BA
Abstains: JH
Motion to adjourn passes. Meeting adjourned at 1:42pm.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sreehari Kalloormana</name></author><summary type="html">Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minutes 2023-09-27</title><link href="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/09/27/minutes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minutes 2023-09-27" /><published>2023-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/09/27/minutes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/09/27/minutes.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;minutes---programming-and-hacking-communities-meeting&quot;&gt;Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;9272023-1145am&quot;&gt;9/27/2023, 11:45am&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Chair:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Rose Wong&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Secretary:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Bilal Abdulrahman&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Present:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Mikael Vejdemo Johansson (MVJ), Jonathan Hanon (JH), Bilal Abdulrahman (BA), Mark Schramm (MS), Zhiyuan Jin (ZJ), Edward Miller (EM), Joshua Rollins (JR), Rose Wong (RW)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting called to order at 12:41pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal-for-agenda&quot;&gt;Proposal for agenda:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approving the agenda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approval of the previous minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unfinished Business&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull requests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion moved by MVJ. Motion was approved to move Unfinished Business above Pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-1-approving-the-agenda&quot;&gt;Item 1. Approving the Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda moved by MVJ, seconded by BA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda carries unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-1-approving-the-minutes&quot;&gt;Item 1. Approving the Minutes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion to replace JH by MVJ in line 36 of minutes.
Motion passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion to fix initials spelling on line 42.
Motion passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion to fix replace spelling on line 65.
Motion passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion to suspend rules and collect all typos by EM.
Motion passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda carries unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion to Recess by MVJ for education purposes 1:00 pm.
Passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recess ended by chair at 1:07pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-3-unfinished-business&quot;&gt;Item 3. Unfinished Business&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider Pull request 260 from BA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amendment by MVJ to fix rule number, file name is 311, fix amendment spelling.
Passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amendment by JH to remove by the proposal of the motion and to remove the gender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion to call question by JH.
Passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amendment passed unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion to amend by JR to make wording more precise.
Motion to amend the amendment by JH to force chair to ask the proposer.
Motion to call to question by JH.
Passed unanimously.
Motion to call to question by BA.
Passed unanimously.
Amendment passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion to call to question by MVJ.
Passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main Motion passed unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we consider pull request 280.
Amendment to fix layout and spelling by MVJ.
Approved by proposer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amendment to add to the secretary.
Approved by proposer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amendment to add by majority vote by EM.
Approved by proposer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion to call question.
Approved by 2/3 majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main Motion was rejected.
EM, MVJ, MS, JH nays.
BA, JR, ZJ ayes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting adjourned at 1:45pm.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bilal Abdulrahman</name></author><summary type="html">Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minutes 2023-09-20</title><link href="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/09/20/minutes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minutes 2023-09-20" /><published>2023-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/09/20/minutes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/09/20/minutes.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;minutes---programming-hacking-and-communities-meeting&quot;&gt;Minutes - Programming Hacking and Communities Meeting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;9202023-1145am&quot;&gt;9/20/2023, 11:45am&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Chair:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Jonathan Hanon (substituting for Joshua Rollins)&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Secretary:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Mark Schramm&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Present:
Mikael Vejdemo Johansson (MVJ), Jonathan Hanon (JH), Bilal Abdulrahman (BA), Mark Schramm (MS), Zhiyuan Jin (ZJ), Edward Miller (EM), Sreehari Kalloormana (SK), Rose Wong (RW)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absent:
Joshua Rollins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting called to order at 12:10pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal-for-agenda&quot;&gt;Proposal for agenda&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approval of Agenda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approval of Minutes of previous meetings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subcommittee Report&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unfinished Business&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluations of PR&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-1-approving-the-agenda&quot;&gt;Item 1. Approving the agenda&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda moved by MVJ and passes unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-2-review-of-previous-9-13s-minutes&quot;&gt;Item 2. Review of previous 9-13’s minutes.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion made to update MVJ’s points from -2.5 to -20 in recalculation of points from failed rule-change. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH moves to correct initials ZI to ZJ and MIJ to MVJ. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RW moves to approve minutes. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-3-subcommittee-pr-formatting-report&quot;&gt;Item 3. Subcommittee (PR formatting) report&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MS moves to merge PR formatting template. After amendments from RW, MS and MVJ are approved, motion passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-4-unfinished-business&quot;&gt;Item 4. Unfinished Business&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves to amend PR 7 (then proposal 202) by adding &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/michiexile/cuny-nomic/pull/7/commits/b5e34cfb41cb3cbcaef74e75c1b04750d321d031&quot;&gt;text to give instructors a 50% point-gain handicap&lt;/a&gt; so the proposed rule doesn’t conflict with a previous rule.
Motion passes unanimously and PR is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RW leaves the room at 12:40&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MVJ moves proposal 202 onto table.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SK raises the issue that rule numbers are not being assigned in accordance with rule 108 and 202 is tabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rule number fixes are unanimously approved and proposal 306 (previously 202) is back on table. 306 passes unanimously.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EM moves proposal 307.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH moves to amend 307 to replace “unanimous vote” with “unanimous vote of other players”. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH moves to amend 307 to replace “winner” with “leader”. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA moves to amend 307 to replace “lose/loss of 10 points” to “lose/loss of 50 points”. Passes. Nays: EM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA moves to amend 307 to change  “In the event of ties, and multiple players reach 10 points of winning” to “In the event that multiple players reach within 10 points” Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA calls the question on 307. Passes. Nays: SK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proposal 307 fails to pass. Ayes: EM, Abstentions: MS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JH moves to amend rule 308 to subtract instead of add 10 points to a players score when they vote against an amendment that passes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA moves to amend proposal to a 5 point subtraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RW moves to amend amend the 5 to 0. Fails to pass. Ayes: RW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA’s amendment passes. Nays: EM, RW, and ZJ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JH’s amendment passes unanimously.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZJ moves proposal 309 which resets the every player’s points to 10 and prevents future resets.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH moves to amend the wording to “At the point of adoption of this rule, all player’s points reset to 10” to keep rule in accoradance with rule 107. Amendment passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZJ’s proposal passes. Nays: BA, Abstentions: RW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZJ moves to amend 302 to change quorum to 3 students or half of membership (5 total).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EM moves to amend ZJ’s amendment to remove “or half of membership (5 total)”. Passes, Nays: RW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZJ’s amendment passes. Nays: RW.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BH’s unfinished business is postponed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH moves to adjourn meeting at 1:50. Passes unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mark Schramm</name></author><summary type="html">Minutes - Programming Hacking and Communities Meeting</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minutes 2023-09-13</title><link href="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/09/13/minutes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minutes 2023-09-13" /><published>2023-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/09/13/minutes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/09/13/minutes.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;minutes---programming-and-hacking-communities-meeting&quot;&gt;Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;9132023-1145am&quot;&gt;9/13/2023, 11:45am&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Chair:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Sreehari Kalloormana&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Secretary:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Edward Miller&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Present:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Mikael Vejdemo Johansson (MVJ), Jonathan Hanon (JH), Bilal Abdulrahman (BA), Mark Schramm(MS), Zhiyuan Jin (ZJ), Edward Miller (EM), Sreehari Kalloormana (SK), Joshua Rollins (JR)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting called to order at 1:10pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ZJ not in meeting when called to order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal-for-agenda&quot;&gt;Proposal for agenda:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approving of Agenda
Approving the minutes of the previous meeting
Approving the subcommittee proposal
Evaluating pull requests
Unfinished business
New business&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-1-approving-the-agenda&quot;&gt;Item 1. Approving the Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agenda moved by MNJ, seconded by JH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BI proposes to amend agenda to switch items 3 and 4,
ZJ entered meeting at 1:11pm and proposal seconded by ZJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amendment to agenda to switch 3 and 4 passes by majority voting against EM, SK, MS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amendment to agenda to delete item 3 and move item to 5a under unfinished passes by majority, voting against EM and JH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amended Agenda carries by majority vote, voting against EM, BA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-2-approving-the-minutes-of-the-previous-meeting&quot;&gt;Item 2. Approving the minutes of the previous meeting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH proposes correction of minutes to correct spelling of Mark Schramm’s name to previous minutes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Correction of minutes passes with no objections&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minutes approved as corrected with majority vote, voting against: ZJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-3-evaluating-pull-requests&quot;&gt;Item 3. Evaluating pull requests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pull requests created by MVJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA proposes Rule F23 evaluated first, MVJ seconded.
Proposal to evaluate F23 first passes by majority, voting against: EM, ZJ, JR
Proposal to treating week old pull requests as unfinished business passes by majority, voting against: EM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ proposes to amend F23 rule to change spelling from ‘nae’ to ‘nay’
Amendment passes with no objections.
Amended F23 rule passes by majority: voting against EM, JR, MS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SK as chair evaluates next pull request – Rule 303
MVJ proposes to amend 303 formatting.
Proposal passes with no objection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Withdrawal of 303 change passes by majority: voting against JH
MVJ proposes to consider 208 next.
Proposal passes by majority, voting against EM, ZI, JC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA proposes amendment to rule change by keeping point system in place but that game ends at the end of the semester., and the player with the most points wins.
Amendment passes with majority vote Voting against: ZJ, JH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule change for 208 defeated by voting against JH, MS, ZJ, EM, JC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SK motions to adjourn, motion approved unanimously.
Meeting adjourned at 1:57 pm&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Edward Miller</name></author><summary type="html">Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting 9/13/2023, 11:45am</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minutes 2023-09-06</title><link href="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/09/06/minutes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minutes 2023-09-06" /><published>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/09/06/minutes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/09/06/minutes.html">&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Chair:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Bilal AbdulRahman&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Secretary:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Jin, Zhiyuan&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Present:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Mikael Vejdemo Johansson (MVJ), Jonathan Hanon (JH), Bilal Abdulrahman (BA), Mark Schramm (MS), Zhiyuan Jin (ZJ), Edward Miller (EM), Sreehari Kalloormana (SK), Joshua Rollins (JR), Rose Wong (RW)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting called to order at 1:00 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proposal for the agenda:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approval of the agenda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approval of the previous minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hearing subcommittee report&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evaluate pull requests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unfinished business&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;item1-approval-of-the-agenda&quot;&gt;item1: Approval of the agenda:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vote: Passed unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;item2-approval-of-the-previous-minutes&quot;&gt;item2: Approval of the previous minutes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;against: none
abstain: rose
Result: Passed by majority&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;item3-hearing-committee-report--pull-request-formatting-guidelines&quot;&gt;item3: Hearing committee report:  Pull request formatting guidelines&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;propose for Postpone of pull request formatting until next week: 
Result: passed by the majority
Disagree:  Joshua, Mark&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;item4-evaluate-pull-requests&quot;&gt;item4: Evaluate pull requests:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Item_a: Pull#3 (update 202) 
Against: Joshua
Result: passed majority&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Item_b: Pull#4 (203-add 10 point gain in rule adoption)
Against: (Joshua, Mark)
Result:  passed by the majority&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Item_c: Pull#5 (206- reduce pull request penalty)
Against: (Rose, Ed, Jonathan, Bilal)
Result: passed by the majority&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Item_d: Pull#6 (update 201.md to remove the notion of turns)
Against: (all of the voters)
Result: Rejected&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-unfinished-business&quot;&gt;no unfinished business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-new-business&quot;&gt;no new business&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Zhiyuan Jin</name></author><summary type="html">Meeting Chair: Bilal AbdulRahman</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minutes 2023-08-30</title><link href="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/08/30/minutes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minutes 2023-08-30" /><published>2023-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/08/30/minutes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://michiexile.github.io/cuny-nomic/2023/08/30/minutes.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;minutes---programming-and-hacking-communities-meeting&quot;&gt;Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;8302023-1145am&quot;&gt;8/30/2023, 11:45am&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Chair:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Mikael Vejdemo-Johansson&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Meeting Secretary:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Jonathan Hanon&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Present:&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Mikael Vejdemo Johansson (MVJ), Jonathan Hanon (JH), Bilal Abdulrahman (BA), Mark Schramm (MS), Zhiyuan Jin (ZJ), Edward Miller (EM), Sreehari Kalloormana (SK), Joshua Rollins (JR), Rose Wong (RW)&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meeting called to order at 12:54pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proposal-for-agenda&quot;&gt;Proposal for agenda:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approving the agenda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull requests created by MVJ&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presidium assignments for the semester&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-1-approving-the-agenda&quot;&gt;Item 1. Approving the Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda moved by MVJ, seconded by JH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JR proposes to amend the agenda to include “Formatting of pull requests and commits” as a new item, seconded by RW&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amendment to proposed agenda approved unanimously as Item 4 for the Proposed agenda, we return to discussing the agenda&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agenda carries unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-2-pull-requests-created-by-mvj&quot;&gt;Item 2. Pull requests created by MVJ&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion by JH to suspend the rules and allow the three pull requests to allow the three rule changes to be able to be considered as one unit, seconded by BA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motion approves unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule change carries unanimously&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-3-presidium-assignments-for-the-semester&quot;&gt;Item 3. Presidium assignments for the semester&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ presents the calendar for the schedule of meetings to the assembly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The assembly agrees to allow MVJ to schedule presiding officers for each meeting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-4-formatting-of-pull-requests-and-commits&quot;&gt;Item 4. Formatting of pull requests and commits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JR inquires about the formatting of pull requests and commits&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BA proposes a template for a format to follow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves to form a subcommittee on formatting of pull requests and commits, JH seconds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MVJ moves that the proposed subcommittee compose JR, BA, MS, and RW, with a deadline for them to propose a format by the next meeting, JR seconds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH inquires if the members would agree to serve, the members agree&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The motion on the composition carries, we return to the motion to form a subcommittee with said composition&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subcommittee forms unanimously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;item-5-new-business&quot;&gt;Item 5. New Business&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No new business introduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JH motions to adjourn, MVJ seconds, motion approved unanimously&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonathan Hanon</name></author><summary type="html">Minutes - Programming and Hacking Communities Meeting</summary></entry></feed>